A Guide to the Papers of J. Harry Michael, 1958-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of J. Harry Michael, 1958-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10071-g
This collection consists of 1500 items (14 Hollinger boxes).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library by the Honorable J. Harry Michael, Federal Building, Charlottesville, Virginia, on April 2 1992.
Scope and Content Information
This collection, 1958-1986, of ca. 1500 items (14 Hollinger boxes) consists mainly of calendars maintained by J. Harry Michael, judge of the United States District Court for the Western District of Virginia, invitations to local events and correspondence. There are three types of calendars in this collection: Michael's desk calendar, in which he writes important appointments and conferences; his pocket calendar, which chronicle his court dates; and his calendar/diaries, in which he records business lunches and dinners, social engagements and evening speaking engagements. The invitations pertain mostly to social and business engagements in Charlottesville and Albemarle County, coming from a wide variety of sources, ranging from family friends to banks. Invitations of note include the announcement of the Virginia Association of Defense Attorneys lunch (October 2, 1982), the details of Michael's "tiger cruise" on the USS Scott (November 30-December 3, 1983) and the annual announcement of the Taft Seminar for Teachers. Correspondence in the collection is varied in nature; there are some letters of a personal nature, but most pertain to court or community business. Correspondents of note include then Chief Justice of the Supreme Court Warren Burger (July 31, 1986); James Turk, then Chief Justice of the U.S. District Court in Western Virginia (1984-1987); John W. Warner (July 2, 1985); and, Robert E. Maxwell (July 1987). A large part of the correspondence is devoted to Michael's attempt to have a U.S. deputy marshal assigned to Charlottesville. There are also letters and memos from the Federal Judicial Center and the Administrative Offices of the U. S. Courts. Wayne P. Beamon is also a major correspondent concerning the assignment of a U.S. deputy marshall to Charlottesville.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1980-1987, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: Adminstrative Office of the U.S. Courts 1980-1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Assignment of Deputy U.S. Marshall to Charlottesville 1980-1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with the Federal Judicial Center Re: S2572 July 8, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Tax Policy Round Table 1980-1985 (Box 2)
- Topical
  - Calendars: Calendar of Events for the Commonwealth of Virginia January-September, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Calendars: Council of State Governments January-September, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Desk Calendar December, 1969- April, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Desk Calendar 1970, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Desk Calendar 1971-1973, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Desk Calendar January- June, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Desk Calendar July- December, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Desk Calendar 1975-1977, 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Desk Calendar January- June, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Desk Calendar July-December, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Desk Calendar 1979-1981, 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Desk Calendar 1982-1984, 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Desk Calendar January-June, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Desk Calendar July-December, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Desk Calendar 1986, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Invitations and Schedules 1979-1980 (Box 7)
  - Invitations 1981, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Invitations 1982, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Invitations: Va. Association of Defense Attorneys' Lunch October 2, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Invitations 1983, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Invitations: USS Scott (DDG 995) Tiger Cruise November 30-December 3, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Invitations 1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Invitations January-August, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Invitations April 1986, 1987, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Invitations: Taft Seminar for Teachers 1982-1986 (Box 9)
  - Pocket Calendars with court dates 1958-1961, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Pocket Calendars with Court Dates 1973-1976 (Box 9)
  - Pocket Calendars with Court Dates 1977-1979 (Box 9)
  - Pocket Calendars with court dates 1981-1986 (Box 10)
  - Printed Material 1981-1984 (Box 10)
  - Travel Reservations 1981-1984 (Box 10)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit; General and Case Information 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1967-1968, Bound Volume, 2 volumes (Box 10)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1969-1972, Bound Volume, 4 volumes (Box 11)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1973-1976, Bound Volumes, 4 volumes (Box 12)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1973-1976, Bound Volumes, 4 volumes (Box 12)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1977-1980, Bound Volumes, 4 volumes (Box 13)
  - Diaries/Calendars 1981-1983, Bound Volumes, 3 volumes (Box 14)